The shutdown of the Strait of Hormuz was
霍尔木兹海峡的关闭情况可能
not quite as bad as you probably
没有你
thought. It is true that in retaliation
想象的那么糟糕。 确实，为了报复
for the US and Israel strikes in Iran,
美国和以色列对伊朗的袭击，
the country's SEPA Navy broadcast the
该国的东南太平洋海军
following message over [music] VHF
通过[音乐]甚高频
marine radio.
海上无线电广播了以下信息。
&gt;&gt; From now on, all navigating through the
从现在起，所有通过
Strait of Hormuz is forbidden. No ship
霍尔木兹海峡的航行都将被禁止。 在下次[音乐]通知发布之前，
in every type is not allowed to pass
任何类型的船舶都不得
from the Strait of Hormuz till next
通过霍尔木兹海峡
[music] notice.
。
&gt;&gt; To back up that declaration, the Iran
为了支持这一声明，伊朗
Revolutionary Guard Corps attacked
革命卫队用导弹和无人机袭击了
vessels that dared try to transit the
胆敢试图通过该
waterway with missiles and drones,
水道的船只，
sending a clear message to others,
向其他国家发出明确的信号，
grinding [music] traffic to a halt. It's
使（音乐）交通陷入瘫痪。
also true that 20% of the world's oil
同样不可否认的是，直到战争爆发前，世界上 20% 的石油都要
passed through this choke point up until
经过这个咽喉要道
the war.
。
&gt;&gt; [music]
[音乐]
&gt;&gt; But global oil production in March 2026
但 2026 年 3 月全球石油产量
actually only shrunk about 8%. Prices,
实际上只下降了约 8%。
however, spiked a massive 60%, seven and
然而，价格却飙升了 60%，是供应
a half times more than the contraction
减少幅度的七倍半
in supply.
。
This is perhaps counterintuitive, but
这或许有悖常理，但这
how this happened and what happens next
一切是如何发生的以及接下来会发生什么，
is [music] explained by the full
[音乐]可以用
complexity of the global oil markets.
全球石油市场的复杂性来解释。
The Gulf is undoubtedly the world's most
毫无疑问，海湾地区是世界上最
important oil production region. It has
重要的石油生产区。 它拥有
both the greatest reserves and the
最大的储量和
lowest cost of production, making it no
最低的生产成本，因此
surprise that it quickly developed into
它迅速发展成为
one of the world's greatest
世界上最富有的
concentrations of wealth. The smallest
财富集中地之一也就不足为奇了。
country on the waterway, Bahrain, no
巴林是这条水道上最小的国家，
larger than the city of New York, is
面积甚至不及纽约市，但它
still the world's 35th largest oil
仍然是世界第 35 大石油
producer, outputting about 200,000
生产国，日产量约为 20
barrels a day, even though its economy
万桶，尽管其经济
is fairly well diversified away from oil
已经相当多元化，不再完全依赖石油
extraction. It focuses a good bit on
开采。 它重点关注
refining oil from Saudi Arabia, as well
沙特阿拉伯的石油提炼，
as manufacturing, finance, and other
以及制造业、金融业和其他
sectors. Neighboring Qatar is similar.
行业。 邻国卡塔尔的情况也类似。
It's the next largest Gulf producer at
它是海湾地区第二大石油生产国，日产量为
1.3 million barrels a day, though it too
130 万桶，不过它也
has diversified its economy by
通过
specializing in natural gas production.
专注于天然气生产实现了经济多元化。
Its Ras Laffan Industrial City is
其拉斯拉凡工业城
single-handedly responsible for 20% of
独自承担了全球 20% 的
the world's liquid natural gas supply.
液化天然气供应。
Then there's Kuwait, the world's [music]
还有科威特，它是世界第十大[音乐]
10th largest producer at 2.6 million
生产国，日产量达 260 万桶
barrels a day. Though in this case,
。 不过就目前情况来看，
there's little diversification. Oil
多元化程度并不高。 石油
completely dominates the small country's
完全主导着这个小国的
economy. These three nations, Bahrain,
经济。 由于海峡关闭，巴林、
Qatar, and Kuwait, were put in a tricky,
卡塔尔和科威特这三个国家陷入了棘手的、
almost existential situation by the
几乎是生死攸关的境地，
closure of the strait as they're each
因为它们都
100% reliant on oil tankers transiting
100%依赖油轮通过这条
the waterway to export their product.
水道出口石油产品。
&gt;&gt; [music]
[音乐]
&gt;&gt; It was absolutely devastating to their
这对它们的
economies, but less so to the global
经济造成了毁灭性的打击，但对全球
economy as they collectively
经济的影响较小，因为它们加起来只占
represent just 16% of Gulf oil
海湾石油产量的 16%
production. Their influence on global
。 它们对全球
prices is rather minimal.
价格的影响微乎其微。   但
The rest of the Gulf countries though
海湾其他国家的情况则
are in a very different,
截然不同，
&gt;&gt; [music]
[音乐]
&gt;&gt; more promising situation. The next
前景更加光明。 第二
largest producer, the United Arab
大生产国
Emirates, produces about 4.1 million
阿拉伯联合酋长国每天生产约 410 万桶
barrels a day, more than [music] the
原油，比
previous three combined, but crucially,
前三个生产国的总和还要多，但关键是，
it has a small coastline on the other
它在海峡的另一侧拥有一小段海岸线
side of the strait.
。
&gt;&gt; [music]
[音乐]
&gt;&gt; Most Emirati production is in or near
阿联酋的大部分石油生产都在
the Gulf as that's where the oil
海湾地区或附近，因为那里蕴藏着丰富的石油资源
physically is, but in 2008, it started
，但2008年，阿联酋开始
building a pipeline. While official
修建一条输油管道。 虽然官方
government statements tended to focus on
政府声明往往侧重于
bypassing [music] the strait, the true
通过海峡出口音乐所节省的成本和时间，但其真正
purpose was hardly a secret. Iran had
目的几乎是公开的秘密。 伊朗
long threatened to shut down the Strait
长期以来一直威胁要封锁
of Hormuz, and the UAE knew they could
霍尔木兹海峡，而阿联酋也知道他们实际上有能力
actually do it. [music] It's only 20
做到这一点。  [音乐] 它只有 20
miles wide, the shipping lanes are even
英里宽，航道更
smaller, and all they'd have to do is
窄，他们只需要
lay some mines or launch some rockets to
布设一些水雷或发射一些火箭就能
keep ships [music] from trying. Well,
阻止船只[音乐]尝试。 嗯，
before the war, a substantial portion of
在战争爆发之前，
the UAE's oil was loaded onto tankers at
阿联酋的大部分石油在达斯岛装上油轮
Das Island, a slim majority was sent via
，略多于大部分石油通过
the pipeline and loaded at the port of
管道输送到
Fujairah, meaning the country was
富查伊拉港装船，这意味着
already fairly [music] resilient when
当
this strategic threat came into reality.
这一战略威胁成为现实时，该国已经相当具有韧性。
Iran itself, the world's seventh largest
伊朗是世界第七大音乐
producer, has actually, [music] perhaps
生产国，但
counterintuitively, developed a very
出乎意料的是，它在音乐领域也发展出了非常
similar strategy. Prior to the war, its
类似的策略。 战前，其
primary [music] export point was Kharg
主要（音乐）出口点是哈尔格
Island. Like with the UAE and most of
岛。 与阿联酋及其大多数
its neighboring countries, the Iranian
邻国一样，伊朗
Gulf shoreline is fairly shallow, so
海湾的海岸线相当浅，因此
this island, connecting to oil fields by
这座通过管道与油田相连的岛屿，
pipeline, allows large tankers to dock
允许大型油轮停靠
[music] and load to full capacity.
并满载装载。
Despite Iran's 4.2 million barrels a day
尽管伊朗每天生产 420 万桶原油
of production, 90% was exported via this
，但其中 90% 都通过这
one terminal, an incredible
一个码头出口，这是一个惊人的
concentration. But just as other Gulf
集中度。 但正如其他海湾
countries were worried about Iran
国家担心伊朗
shutting down the Strait of Hormuz, so
封锁霍尔木兹海峡一样，
too was Iran for its foes, so it built
伊朗也担心其敌人会这样做，因此它修建了
[music] its own pipeline to the other
自己的管道，将音乐输送到
side of the strait. The port of Jask was
海峡的另一边。 战前雅斯克港
rarely used in practice prior to the
很少被实际使用
war, but it's believed it could handle
，但据信凭借现有基础设施，它可以处理
about 15% of normal export flows with
大约 15% 的正常出口流量，
existing infrastructure and more with
经过
some upgrades.
一些升级后，处理能力还可以更强。
Iraq, however, [music] is in a slightly
然而，伊拉克的音乐
different situation. Its Gulf coastline
情况则略有不同。 它的墨西哥湾海岸线
is tiny. It uses offshore platforms to
很短。 它利用海上平台
[music] load tankers that carry the vast
装载油轮，这些油轮运输了
majority of its oil, but unlike the UAE
其绝大部分石油，但与阿联酋
and Iran, it has no other coastline
和伊朗不同，除了海峡之外，它没有其他海岸线
beyond the strait. Instead, it has a
。 相反，它有一条通往
pipeline to a port in Turkey [music]
土耳其港口的管道（音乐），
and on paper, this is hugely
从理论上讲，这具有巨大的
strategically significant, perhaps even
战略意义，甚至可能
more so than the UAE [music] and Iran's
比阿联酋（音乐）和伊朗的
pipelines. Not only does this bypass the
管道更重要。 这不仅可以绕过
Strait of Hormuz, but also the Suez
霍尔木兹海峡，还可以绕过苏伊士运河，而
Yemen. In practice though, Iraq's
苏伊士运河近年来由于也门胡塞武装袭击船只，贸易航线一直断断续续。 但实际上，
pipeline is itself fickle thanks to the
由于
country's tenuous politics. It's [music]
伊拉克不稳定的政治局势，这条输油管道本身也难以预测。 它的音乐
routed through the ethnically distinct
源自库尔德斯坦这个民族独特的
region of Kurdistan, which while part of
地区，虽然
Iraq, has its own autonomous government
库尔德斯坦是伊拉克的一部分，但它拥有自己的自治政府，
and in many ways acts as a separate
并在许多方面表现得像一个独立的
[music] state. Kurdistan's government
音乐国家。 库尔德斯坦政府
constantly quarrels with Baghdad over
不断与巴格达就其
whether it has the right to export oil
是否有权独立出口石油发生争执
independently and uses the pipeline as
，并将该管道作为
leverage, meaning the political winds of
筹码，这意味着当前的政治风向
the moment dictate whether this pipeline
决定了这条管道
[music] actually works in practice. Over
（音乐）在实践中是否真的有效。
recent years, it's predominantly been in
近年来，该基地主要处于
a non-operative state, but this shifted
非运作状态，但随着霍尔木兹海峡的关闭，这种情况发生了改变
weeks into the war. It's believed
。战争爆发几周后，巴格达、库尔德斯坦和土耳其达成协议，关闭了霍尔木兹海峡。 据信，
[music] that in time, this route could
随着时间的推移，这条路线的日运输量可能会
ramp up to 600,000 barrels a day,
增加到 60 万桶，
representing close to 15% of pre-war
接近战前出口总量的 15%
export totals.
。
Lastly, there's Saudi Arabia, the Gulf's
最后，还有沙特阿拉伯，海湾地区
definitive [music]
当之无愧的[音乐]
oil production giant. It is the only
石油生产巨头。 它是
Gulf country with a Red Sea coastline,
海湾地区唯一拥有红海海岸线的国家，
and it's taken advantage of this to
并利用这一优势
build a massively capable contingency
建立了一套能力强大的应急
plan. It's 750-mi 1,200-km [music]
预案。 这条长 750 英里（1200 公里）的
east-west pipeline was built in response
东西向输油管道是为了应对
to the Iran-Iraq War in the '80s, and
80 年代的两伊战争而修建的。
while Iran never closed the strait
虽然伊朗
during this conflict, [music] both it
在这场冲突中从未关闭过海峡，但伊朗
and its enemy attacked tankers in the
和它的敌人都袭击了
Gulf, and Saudi Arabia believed a
海湾的油轮。沙特阿拉伯认为，
closure could be a natural evolution of
关闭海峡可能是这一战略的自然演变
the strategy. It's not entirely clear
。 目前还不完全清楚
exactly how much capacity [music] the
该
country could divert via this route.
国可以通过这条途径转移多少（音乐）资源。
While the pipeline itself can operate at
虽然该管道本身每天可以输送
as much as 5 million barrels a day, and
高达 500 万桶原油，并且如果将
day by converting its parallel natural
其平行的天然气
gas line to carry crude as well, [music]
管道也改造为输送原油，则有可能每天输送高达 700 万桶原油，但[音乐]
analysts believe the bigger constraint
分析师认为，更大的限制
is the tanker loading terminals at its
是其
terminus, the Port of Yanbu, citing
终点站延布港的油轮装载码头，指出其
capacity. Regardless, [music] that's a
容量可能只有每天 500 万桶。 不管怎样，音乐就像
tremendous amount of oil. So much so
石油一样，蕴藏着巨大的能量。 即便
producer despite the closure of the
海峡关闭，沙特阿拉伯仍然保持着世界第三大石油生产国的地位
strait.
。
Collectively, these four pipelines
这四条管道加起来
provide considerable export capacity,
提供了相当大的出口能力，
dampening the impact of the strait's
减轻了海峡
closure. And that's added to the fact
关闭的影响。 除此之外，
that even as Iran blockaded the strait,
即使伊朗封锁了海峡，仍有
a drip feed of tankers were getting
少量油轮得以
through. So far, these have
通过。 到目前为止，这些
predominantly been those exporting
主要是出口
Iranian oil or linked to Iranian allies,
伊朗石油或与伊朗盟友有关联的国家，
but regardless,
但无论如何，
&gt;&gt; [music]
考虑到石油是一个全球市场，
supply these carry provides downward
这些国家的石油供应
pressure on global oil prices. While the
对全球油价构成了下行压力。 虽然
supply shock certainly has been bad,
供应冲击确实很糟糕，但
when you add these all together, it's
把所有这些因素加起来，其影响
potentially smaller than what the
可能比
headlines might imply. So, why does an
新闻标题所暗示的要小。 那么，为什么
8% contraction in supply lead to a 60%
供应减少 8% 会导致
jump in price?
价格上涨 60% 呢？
Well, there's a concept in economics
嗯，经济学中有一个概念
called elasticity of demand.
叫做需求弹性。
Effectively, it's the relationship
实际上，这就是
between price and demand. For example,
价格与需求之间的关系。 例如，
breakfast cereal is typically a fairly
早餐麦片通常是一种
elastic product. Considering buying one
弹性较大的产品。 购买某个
particular brand is not necessary, it's
特定品牌并非必要，这
just a preference, the price charged
只是个人偏好，价格在
influences people's decision-making a
很大程度上影响着人们的决策
good bit, at least on average. Academic
，至少平均而言是这样。 学术
research has shown its average
研究表明，音乐的平均
elasticity of demand is -3, meaning a
需求弹性为 -3，这意味着
10% increase in prices will [music] lead
价格上涨 10% 将
to a 30% drop in demand. Consumers will
导致需求下降 30%。 消费者
just buy another brand or switch to
只会购买其他品牌或改吃
something else for breakfast. There are
其他早餐食品。 有
plenty of substitutes. This also works
很多替代品。 反过来也一样适用
in the inverse. If there's too much
。 如果
demand for a particular brand of cereal,
某种品牌的谷物需求过大，
more than can be manufactured, then the
超过了生产能力，那么该
brand knows that they can raise prices
品牌就知道，他们可以
10% for every 30% drop in demand they
通过每降低 30% 的需求量就提价 10%，
want to induce, [music] thereby allowing
从而实现
them to optimize revenue.
收入最大化。
This concept also applies to the oil
这一概念同样适用于石油
market. In March, there was about an 8%
市场。  3月份，供应量减少了约8%
contraction in supply, so prices rose to
，因此价格上涨以
get rid of a corresponding amount of
消除相应的
demand. The problem, though, is that oil
需求。 但问题在于，石油
is an incredibly inelastic product.
是一种极缺乏弹性的产品。
Unlike breakfast cereal, there's really
与早餐麦片不同，
no immediate substitute for oil.
食用油目前还没有真正意义上的替代品。
Internal combustion vehicles just simply
内燃机汽车只
need oil to run. And the way vehicles
需要机油就能运转。 车辆的
are used is hard to change, too. Among
使用方式也很难改变。
personal vehicles, for example, 3/4 of
例如，在美国，私家车出行中，四分之三是非
non-discretionary journeys like
必要出行，例如
commuting, buying groceries, dropping
通勤、购买杂货、送
kids off at school, etc. [music]
孩子上学等。[音乐]
And even among discretionary trips,
即使是非必要出行，例如
heading out to eat, driving to the gym,
外出就餐、开车去健身房、
going on a weekend road trip, people
周末自驾游，人们也
mostly won't let gas price increases
大多不会因为油价上涨而
dissuade them from doing what they want
放弃自己想做的事情
to do. Even if people learn to cut back
。 即使人们学会减少
on driving or switch to public
开车或改用公共
transport, personal vehicles only
交通工具，私家车也
account for about a quarter of global
只占全球
oil use. The rest is commercial, and a
石油消耗量的四分之一左右。 其余部分都是商业性的，而
trucking company certainly isn't going
货运公司当然不会
to stop trucking because oil prices are
因为油价上涨就停止货运
up. They'll charge more, which might
。 他们会提高价格，这
reduce demand eventually, but not in the
最终可能会降低需求，但短期内不会
short term. Long-term elasticity of
。 长期
demand is different. People will
需求弹性有所不同。 人们
eventually buy EVs, shorten their
最终会购买电动汽车，缩短
commute, and make other choices that
通勤时间，并做出其他
reduce oil use, but in the short term,
减少石油使用的选择，但在短期内，
academic research looking at historical
研究历史先例的学术研究
precedent suggests oil has an elasticity
表明，石油的
of demand of around -0.1.
需求弹性约为 -0.1。
The opening weeks of the war in Iran
伊朗战争的最初几周
largely, but don't entirely mesh with
与此大体上吻合，但并不完全吻合
this. Its 8% contraction in supply and
。 其供给减少 8%，
60% price increase implies a -0.13
价格上涨 60%，这意味着
elasticity of demand. And while that's
需求弹性为 -0.13。 虽然这与
close to what theory suggests, it's not
理论预测相近，但还不完全正确
quite there.
。   一些
Anecdotally, experts have backed up this
专家也证实了这种
view. Even the CEO of Exxon has
观点。 就连埃克森美孚的首席执行官也
effectively said he thinks prices are
明确表示，他认为油价
lower than where they should be. But how
低于应有的水平。 但
can a market under react? Well, this
市场怎么可能反应不足呢？ 嗯，这个
market is not perfect. It has subjective
市场并不完美。 它拥有主观上易
fallible actors of incredible influence,
犯错但影响力巨大的参与者，
otherwise known as commodity traders.
也就是我们常说的商品交易员。
This finance sector makes its money by
这个金融行业通过
betting on what oil prices will do in
押注未来石油价格的走势来赚钱，
the future and through that [music] are
而音乐正是
on how oil prices move today. Through a
当今影响石油价格走势的最大人为因素之一。 他们通过
combination of physical oil purchases
实物石油购买
and financial instruments like futures
和期货合约等金融工具
contracts, they move the market ahead of
，抢在供需变化之前左右市场走势
the supply and demand induced moves. For
。
example, if they believe supply will
例如，如果他们认为供应
eminently contract and therefore prices
即将收缩，因此价格
will rise, they'll all rush to buy
将会上涨，他们就会争相购买
physical oil, store it for a moment,
实物石油，暂时储存起来，从而
contracting short-term supply and
收缩短期供应并
raising prices. So, of course, when done
推高价格。 当然，当
at scale, this becomes a self-fulfilling
大规模进行时，这就会变成一种自我实现的
prophecy where what commodity traders
预言，商品交易者
are really betting on, at least in the
真正押注的，至少在
short term, is what other commodity
短期内，是其他商品
traders will do. The effect this has on
交易者会做什么。 这对
the market is that [music] the
市场的影响是，[音乐]的
day-to-day movements follow a mix of
日常发展遵循
narrative and reality. If a large
叙事和现实的混合体。 如果大多数
consensus [music] of traders believe oil
交易员普遍认为
prices will rise, then oil prices will
油价会上涨，那么油价
generally rise. If they believe they'll
通常就会上涨。 如果他们相信自己会
fall, they'll fall.
失败，他们就会失败。
And this helps [music] explain this. In
而这有助于（音乐）解释这一点。 在
Iran, the market's reaction to the
伊朗冲突爆发的最初几天，市场对全球
closure of the single largest oil choke
最大石油咽喉
point in the world was rather muted. The
要道关闭的反应相当平静。
US and Israeli strikes started in the
美国和以色列的空袭始于
early hours of Saturday, February 28th,
2月28日星期六凌晨，这
meaning traders had two whole days when
意味着交易员们有整整两天的
the market was closed to reflect on its
市场休市时间来思考其
implications. And yet, following a full
影响。 然而，经过
day of trading on Monday, prices had
周一一整天的交易，价格
only risen a fairly modest 6%. [music]
仅上涨了相当温和的 6%。  [音乐]
Tuesday's rise was less than 5%. Then
周二的涨幅不到 5%。
Wednesday, the market was effectively
周三，市场基本
flat, even as insurers were canceling
持平，尽管保险公司正在取消
policies and more and more reports were
保单，而且有关海湾地区船只遭到无人机袭击的报道也越来越多
the Gulf.
。   当时的情况
What was happening was [music] that, as
是，音乐，就像以往一样
they always are, commodity traders'
，商品交易员的
decisions were being influenced by
决策受到了
narrative. Among them, there was a
叙事的影响。 在战争
widespread belief in the opening days of
初期，人们普遍认为
the war that it would be a limited,
这将是一场有限的、
short-term conflict. After all, the
短暂的冲突。 毕竟，
Trump's initial statement about the
特朗普总统关于此次袭击的最初声明的第二句话是
strikes read, "Our objective is to
：“我们的目标是
defend the American people by
通过
eliminating imminent threats [music]
消除
from the Iranian regime." Which implies
伊朗政权的迫在眉睫的威胁来保卫美国人民。” 这意味着一次
a limited military operation. Despite
有限的军事行动。 尽管
this administration says and does,
本届政府的言行经常脱节，但
traders took these statements at face
交易员们
value, seemingly based on precedent.
似乎基于先例，对这些声明信以为真。
[music] Whether it was the operation in
[音乐] 无论是
Venezuela to capture Nicolas Maduro, the
抓捕委内瑞拉的尼古拉斯·马杜罗的行动，还是为
response to the killing of two US
报复两名美国
service members, or the June 2025
军人被杀而对叙利亚境内的ISIS目标进行的打击，亦或是2025年6月
operation in Iran itself where the US
美国在伊朗
dropped bunker buster bombs to
投放掩体炸弹以
supposedly [music] obliterate Iranian
摧毁伊朗
nuclear assets, the Trump administration
核设施的行动，特朗普政府
had so far kept the scope of its
迄今为止都将其军事行动的范围控制在
military campaigns limited. After all,
有限之内。 毕竟，
wars tend to be politically unpopular,
战争在政治上往往不受欢迎，
and Trump campaign messaging included
而特朗普的竞选宣传中也
accusations that his opponent would
指责他的对手会
start a war in Iran, implying reluctance
发动对伊朗的战争，暗示他不愿
to let the conflict escalate. So,
让冲突升级。 所以，
traders took the administration at their
交易员们相信了政府的
word, but then reality happened.
话，但现实却并非如此。
You see, as soon as Tehran started
你看，德黑兰一开始向
Middle East, all the world's major
中东发射导弹和无人机，全世界所有主要的
marine insurance companies almost
海洋保险公司几乎
simultaneously published letters like
同时发表了像
[music] this. This is a cancellation
这样的信函。 这是
notice for this insurer's war risk
该保险公司战争险的取消通知
insurance. The value of a very large
。 一艘超大型
crude carrier ranges between 80 and 130
原油运输船的价值在 8000 万至 1.3
million dollars, and even at pre-war oil
亿美元之间，即使按照战前油价计算
prices, its cargo is worth upward of 130
，其货物的价值也超过 1.3
million dollars. This means that ship
亿美元。 这意味着
owners simply have to have insurance.
船东必须购买保险。
It's just too big of a risk for a single
对于一家
company to bear independently. Owners
公司来说，独自承担这样的风险实在太大了。 船东
hold policies for just about every risk
为几乎所有可以想象到的风险都购买了保险
imaginable: groundings, collisions,
：搁浅、碰撞、
breakdowns, fire. But, the major
故障、火灾。 但是，各大
insurers operate an independent body
保险公司运营着一个
called the Joint War Committee that
名为“联合战争委员会”的独立机构，该机构
essentially decides which global regions
实际上决定哪些全球地区
are at high risk for conflict. In recent
面临较高的冲突风险。
years, this has included places like the
近年来，这其中包括
coast of Venezuela, Gulf of Guinea,
委内瑞拉沿海地区、几内亚湾、
Black Sea, Red Sea, and all the waters
黑海、红海以及
near Iran. Within these areas, vessels
伊朗附近的所有水域。 在这些区域内，船舶
are effectively required to carry
实际上需要购买
additional war [music] risk insurance to
额外的战争风险保险，以
cover strikes by missiles, drones,
承保导弹、无人机、
mines, and more. But crucially, these
水雷等造成的袭击。 但关键在于，
policies can be canceled by the insurers
保险公司
with 72-hour notice,
只需提前 72 小时通知即可取消这些保单，
&gt;&gt; [music]
[音乐]
&gt;&gt; and this is exactly what all the
而这正是
insurers did when the war started. This
战争开始时所有保险公司所做的。 这是让
woke the market up to the reality of
市场意识到
this disruption. Regardless of the
这场颠覆性变革现实的最重要情节之一。 撇开
physical impediments, bureaucratic ones
物理障碍不谈，官僚主义的阻碍
made it functionally impossible for oil
实际上使得石油无法
to flow out of the Gulf.
从墨西哥湾流出。
As days turned into weeks, some insurers
随着时间推移，一些保险公司
started writing policies again, but if
开始重新承保，但这
anything, these gave the oil market more
反而让石油市场更加
reason for concern as the cost of war
担忧，因为战争
risk insurance had gone up more than
风险保险的成本上涨了
10-fold, often selling for around 3% of
10 倍以上，每次航程的保费通常约为
the ship's value per journey rather than
船舶价值的 3%，而不是
up to the war. This makes for a massive
战争爆发前几周的 0.1% 到 0.25%。 这造成了巨大的
additional cost that is unlikely [music]
额外成本，而且
to subside soon since hypothetical
由于假设的
threats turned into reality. That's to
威胁变成了现实，这种成本不太可能很快下降。
say, due to this and other changes,
也就是说，由于这一变化以及其他一些变化，
through March, the intractability of the
3 月份
disruption to global oil flows came into
全球石油流动中断的棘手问题逐渐
focus, and the market responded
凸显，市场也做出了
accordingly.
相应的反应。
Even as diversion routes ramped up in
即使在 3 月下半月改道运输的路线增多，
contraction [music] in supply shrunk
供应收缩幅度
smaller, oil prices continued to hover
缩小，油价仍然徘徊在
near $100 a barrel. For every bit of
每桶 100 美元附近。 每
supply that came back online, traders'
恢复一点供应，交易员的
sentiments appeared balanced in the
情绪似乎就会朝着
other direction by growing concern about
另一个方向发展，他们对供应
the potential length of the disruption.
中断可能持续的时间越来越担心，这种情绪似乎与之平衡。
The illusion of Gulf stability has been
海湾地区稳定的假象已经
shattered. Over recent years, as these
破灭。 近年来，随着这些
countries grew wealthier and more
国家变得更加富裕和
developed, the market started to believe
发达，市场开始认为
that they were geopolitically isolated
它们在地缘政治上与更
from the tumult [music] in the broader
广泛的
Middle East. Iran's ability to shut down
中东地区的动荡局势隔绝开来。 伊朗
the entire region's economy overnight
一夜之间瘫痪整个地区的经济，
demonstrated the frailty of that belief,
证明了这种信念的脆弱性，
[music] and so So continued supply of
[音乐] 因此，海湾石油的持续供应
Gulf oil is not as guaranteed as markets
并不像市场在
might have thought before the war began.
战争开始前所认为的那样有保障。
The market will likely price this
市场很可能会
uncertainty in long-term. So until the
在长期内将这种不确定性反映到价格中。 因此，在
Strait of Hormuz is no longer relevant
霍尔木兹海峡
for global oil logistics, the
对全球石油物流不再重要之前，
uncertainty in its continued operation
其持续运营的不确定性
will likely have the entire [music]
可能会让整个
world paying more at the pump.
音乐界付出更高的代价。
You might be surprised to learn that the
你可能会惊讶地发现，
UAE is one of the countries that has
阿联酋是
restricted access to the internet. You
限制互联网访问的国家之一。 在那里你
can't use FaceTime, WhatsApp calls, or
无法使用 FaceTime、WhatsApp 通话或
other internet calling apps there. And
其他网络通话应用。
they also block access to sites that
他们还会屏蔽
they consider a violation of their
他们认为违反其
cultural and religious norms. This is
文化和宗教规范的网站。 这
just one example of the internet not
只是互联网并非
being truly global. Another that I
真正全球化的一个例子。 我
encounter all the time while in Europe
在欧洲经常遇到的另一个问题是，一些规模
is smaller US-focused [music]
较小的、以美国为中心的[音乐]
sites not being accessible due to
网站由于
non-compliance with GDPR regulations.
不符合 GDPR 法规而无法访问。   还有
Then there's the one that almost
一种几乎
everyone does, geo-blocking on streaming
每个人都会做的，那就是在流媒体服务上设置地理位置限制
services. All these problems are ones
。 所有这些问题都是
that our sponsor, NordVPN, solves. They
我们的赞助商 NordVPN 可以解决的。 他们
have hundreds of servers in countries
在世界各地拥有数百台服务器
all around the world, so you can browse
，因此您可以像身处任何地方一样浏览
the internet as if you're pretty much
互联网
anywhere you want. But I think the use
。 但我认为它
that's even more important is for
更重要的用途是
cybersecurity. When you connect to a
网络安全。 连接到
public Wi-Fi network, you're making your
公共 Wi-Fi 网络时，您的
data and activity vulnerable. Someone
数据和活动将面临风险。
move you do unless you use NordVPN. They
除非你使用NordVPN，否则你的一举一动都可能被另一端的人监视。 他们会在
create an encrypted tunnel between you
你
and their secure servers, blocking out
和他们的安全服务器之间创建一个加密隧道，阻止
bad actors. They also do so much more
不良行为者。
even when you're on secure Wi-Fi through
即使您使用 Threat Protection Pro 等工具连接安全的 Wi-Fi，它们也能提供更多功能
tools like Threat Protection Pro.
。
NordVPN is able to detect and block
NordVPN能够检测并阻止
scams, phishing websites, malware,
诈骗、钓鱼网站、恶意软件、
[music] and more. For example,
[音乐]等。 例如，
independent testers found that it was
独立测试人员发现，它
able to detect at least 85% of phishing
能够检测出至少 85% 的钓鱼
websites. If you're on the internet a
网站。 如果你经常上网
lot, I think NordVPN is a critical tool
，我认为 NordVPN 是一款至关重要的工具，而且
that's well justified in time,
随着时间的推移，它的价值也得到了充分体现，
especially since it's pretty affordable,
尤其是它价格相当实惠，
especially if you use our link
特别是如果你使用我们的链接
nordvpn.com/wendover.
nordvpn.com/wendover 的话。
That'll get you an exclusive deal plus 4
这样你就能获得独家优惠，外加 4 个
months extra, and they even have a
月的额外使用时间，他们甚至还提供
30-day money-back guarantee, so give
30 天退款保证，所以不妨访问
them a shot at nordvpn.com/wendover.
nordvpn.com/wendover 试试看。